Guide to the Hoover Institution Archives Motion Picture Films
Hoover Institution Archives
Guide to the Hoover Institution Archives Motion Picture Films
1914-1992
Consult repository
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
This guide describes motion picture films from various collections in the archives. The guide is organized by collection title and includes the number of films, the film gauge(s), and the content matter of the films within each collection. When applicable, the guide lists access copies and external links to online content. Non-film materials may be described in the links provided to the respective guides for each collection.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to each collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Searchworks at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Searchworks is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
The motion picture films in the Hoover Institution Archives collections consist of home movies, documentaries, publicity films, newsreels, television shows, speeches, and many other films that are not commercially available, and are exclusive to the Hoover Institution Archives. The films document historical events such as the dropping of the atomic bomb on Hiroshima and Nagasaki, the Russian Revolution, World War II, and many other events.
This guide describes motion picture films from various collections in the archives. The guide is organized by collection title and includes the number of films, the film gauge(s), and the content matter of the films within each collection. When applicable, the guide lists access copies and external links to online content. Non-film materials may be described in the links provided to the respective guides for each collection.
In order to view materials in the archives, please note the reference copy number(s).
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by collection title.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Motion pictures
- 1914-1936 [Tysioc dziewiecset czternascie tysioc dziewiecset trzydziesci szesc], http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5g50345h (Box 2003C83: Film Shelf)
  The films in the collection relate to Polish history from 1914 to 1936. (2 35mm films)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access. Use copy reference number: 2003c83_v_0003762
- 40th Bomb Group Association, 1943-1995; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt296nd7zg (Box 87017: Film Shelf)
  The films in this collection relate to the activities of the 40th Bomb Group in the China-Burma-India and Pacific Theaters during World War II. (2 16mm films)
  To view films during your visit, please contact the Archives before your arrival. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
- Agnew (Harold Melvin) motion picture film 1945, http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt7d5nd5tn (Box 80060: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film is the original footage that depicts the explosion of atom bombs over Hiroshima and Nagasaki, Japan. (5 16mm films)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access. Use copy reference number: 80060_f_0003766.
- America Committee to Keep Biafra Alive collection, 1967-1970; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt709nf0gw (Box 71031: Film Shelf)
  Films relate to the Nigerian Civil War of 1967-1970. (2 16mm films)
- America First Committee records, 1940-1942; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf9s20075g (Box 42001: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films relate to the issue of American neutrality in World War II. (2 35mm, 16mm films)
- American Council on Education records, 1918-2004; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf6z09n8hd (Box 91002: Film Shelf)
  Unidentified. (1 16mm film)
- Anderson (Frederick Lewis) papers, 1928-1947; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf4290030t (Box 75054: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films consist of home movies and other films relating to WWII air force/bombardment strategy. (26 16mm films)
- Anderson (Ronald S) papers, 1929-1980; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt796nf1s0 (Box 86021: Film Shelf)
  Films relate to education policy in Postwar Japan. (2 8mm, 16mm films)
- Atlantic Council of the United States records, 1990; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf667nb1h6 (Box 82069: Film Shelf)
  Unidentified. (2 16mm films)
- Augusts (Gvido) collection, 1940-1972; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt7f59r9w9 (Box 73027: Film Shelf)
  Latvian motion picture films, including dramas, documentaries, and newsreels, depicting daily life in Latvia, various aspects of Latvian culture, and postwar treatment of events in Latvia during World War II. (19 16mm films)
- Auský (Stanislav A) collection, 1945; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1v19r5hf (Box 81117: Box 7)
  Motion picture films include footage from the Prague Uprising and other European operations during the end of World War II. (3 16mm, 8mm films)
- Axelbank (Herman) Film collection, 1896-1977; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3t1n99r7 (Box 79073: Film Shelf)
  Film collection depicts major events in the twentieth-century Russian history, including the Russian Revolution and World Wars I and II, the tsarist family and court, communist political and military leaders, and scenes of economic, social, and cultural activities in the Soviet Union. (693 35mm films)
  Use copies for"Tsar to Lenin", Reels 1-12, Reels 14-15, Reels 19-26, Reels 29-30, Reel 36, Reels 40-41, Reel 47, Reel 90, Reel 93, Reel 97, and Reel 99 are available for immediate access. To view other films during your visit, please contact the Archives before your arrival. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
- Baez (Albert V) papers, 1972; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf309n99c9 (Box 85011: Box 52)
  Collection contains two educational films about Light, Color and Holography. (2 16mm films)
- Barbour (George B) papers, 1911-1934; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6r29r9k9 (Box 73071: Film Shelf)
  Collection contains a film called"Wheelbarrows with Sails, Peking". (1 16mm film)
- Bellquist (Eric C) papers, 1951; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf567nb0kf (Box 81092: Film Shelf)
  Collection contains a film called"The Living Stream". (1 16mm film)
- Bendetsen (Karl R) papers, 1917-1989; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf0f59n434 (Box 75100: Film Shelf)
  Films contain footage of swearing-in ceremonies performed for and under Karl R. Bendetsen. (2 16mm films)
- Bishop (Francis W) motion picture film, 1930; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt7s2034rw (Box 88081: Film Shelf)
  Film depicts the Russian physiologist Ivan Pavlov, scenes at Pavlov's research laboratories, and street scenes in Leningrad. (1 16mm film)
- Bohannan (Charles T. R) papers, 1915-1985; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf038n973x (Box 78063: Film Shelf)
  Film in this collection pertains to Vietnam. (1 16mm film)
- Bowman (Alfred Connor) papers, 1943-1979; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6r29r9nb (Box 66015: Film Shelf)
  The motion picture film contains footage of Trieste, Italy immediately following World War II. (1 16mm film)
- Brown (Edmund G)Edmund G. Brown Press conference recording 1964, http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt609nf3d0 (Box xx613: Film Shelf)
  Edmund G. Brown, Governor of California (1959-1967), speaks about the death of Herbert Hoover in 1964. Includes the carillon bells in the Hoover Tower playing music in tribute to Herbert Hoover. (1 16mm film)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access: https://archive.org/details/csth_00008
- Bruns (Armin R) motion picture film: This is worth remembering, 1954; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9p30370x (Box 58021: Film Shelf)
  Film of the eightieth birthday celebration for Herbert Hoover at West Branch, Iowa. (1 16mm film)
- Buchman (Alexander H) papers, 1911-2003; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf6199n7s5 (Box 84075: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films in this collection include footage of Leon Trotsky in Mexico as well as footage of China during the Sino-Japanese War. (5 16mm films)
  "Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access. "Trotsky Footage." Use copy reference number: 84075_f_0007971."
- Byers (Clovis E) papers, 1899-1973; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8tx3hff (Box 64016: Film Shelf)
- Caldwell (John K) papers, 1930-1978; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf0j49n407 (Box 76009: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film depicts scenes of daily life in China 1930-1942 and the travels of John Kenneth Caldwell. (19 16mm films)
  "Use copies of some motion pictures in this collection are available for immediate access. "Columbia Country Club et al. - Use copy reference number: 76009_f_0009881. http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PMyaD7D3KMY
  "Flood in China,; Chinese funeral; farewell review 1939 - Use reference copy number 76009_f_0009883 http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tFEpSd6oUpM
  "Motion picture film of San Franciso, Pacific Ocean crossing, and China 1937" https://archive.org/details/csth_000069
- Camera DDR motion picture film, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt4779r70n (Box 99011: Film Shelf)
  Film relates to social and cultural conditions in East Germany 6 16mm films)
- Candle in the wind: motion picture film, 1984; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt400032qs (Box 88008: Film Shelf)
  Collection includes raw footage, outtakes, and original source footage of a film relating to various religious communities within the Soviet Union, and to the relationship between church and state in the Soviet Union. (693 8mm, 16mm films)
- Charles F. Kettering Foundation records, 1933-1984; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt867nf4n1 (Box 85001: Film Shelf)
  Films in the collection relate to education. (23 16mm films)
- Citizens Committee for Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government records, 1949-1958; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt896nc2d6 (Box 52007: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films relate to the recommendations of the two Commissions on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government chaired by Herbert Hoover. (2 16mm films)
- Citizens for Reagan records, 1976; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt7w1036nz (Box 81141: Film Shelf)
  The collection relates to the campaign of Ronald Reagan for the Republican Party presidential nomination in 1976. (162 16mm films)
- Clark (Ed) papers, 1972-1988; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5779r70z (Box 2002C2: box 4)
  Motion picture film relates to Ed Clark's presidential campaign of 1980. (1 16mm film)
- Commonwealth Club of California records, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt3g5032c1 (Box 2003C87: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film shows Edward F. Adams, E. A. Walcott, and the Luncheon Committee. (1 16mm film)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access: https://archive.org/details/csth_000033
- Communism: myth vs. reality: motion picture film, 1962; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt7s2034vf (Box 2003C41: Film Shelf)
  Films are a 38-part series relating to communist regimes and communist movements throughout the world. (36 16mm films)
- Communist massacre in Hué, South Vietnam: motion picture film, 1969; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9290375k (Box 91082: Film Shelf)
  The film relates to the execution of civilians in Hué during the Têt offensive in 1968. (1 16mm film)
- Cronin (Joseph M) papers, 1975; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5c6033w7 (Box 84014: Film Shelf)
  Film about education in Illinois in 1975. (1 16mm film)
- Czech subject collection, 1968; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3f59n5zg (Box XX752: Film Shelf)
  Film in collection is about Czechoslovakia. (1 16mm film)
- Death of Stalin: television program, 1963; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf6h4nb1dm (Box 92048: Film Shelf)
  Raw footage of interviews with Western journalists and Sovietologists, relating to the death of Soviet leader Joseph Stalin in 1953, and to subsequent political change and de-Stalinization in the Soviet Union. (36 16mm films)
- Death Valley days: videotape series, 1964-1965; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt238nd8zn (Box 83093: Box 1)
  Motion picture film of selected episodes of the Western television series starring Ronald Reagan. (7 16mm films)
  Use copies of some motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access.
  "No Gun Behind His Badge." Use copy reference number: 83093_f_0011199.
  "A City is Born." Use copy reference number: 83093_f_0011033.
- Domke (Paul C)audiovisual materials, 1936-1945; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt000030m1 (Box 78027: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films include various scenes from China and other places between 1936-1945. (17 16mm films)
  "Mdme. Chiang Warphanage, Dixie Mission, Paul C. Domke at CBI HQ in Chungking." Use copy reference number: 78027_f_0012803.
- Drenikoff (Kyril) papers, 1977; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6g5013m5 (Box 88009: Film Shelf)
  Unidentified. (3 16mm films)
- Drewes (Steven) motion picture film collection 1936-1940, http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt887036mt (Box 78080: Film Shelf)
  Two films depicting the 1936 Summer Olympics and the destruction of Rouen during World War II. (2 9.5mm films)
- Educational Research Council of America records, 1951-1982; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5779r71g (Box 81094: Film Shelf)
  Films in the collection pertain to mathematics. (41 16mm films)
- Eifler (Carl Frederick) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt358033m5 (Box 2002C74: Film Shelf)
- Eiler (Keith E) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt296nd80g (Box 2005C38: Box 1)
  Home movies from Catalina. (1 16mm film)
- Elliot (John Elbert) papers, 1971-1972; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt109nd6v5 (Box 81095: Film Shelf)
  Films show highlights of the 1971 and 1972 Rose Bowl college football games. (1 super 8mm films)
- Eloesser (Leo) papers, 1929; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6m3nd4p3 (Box 2003C44: Film Shelf)
  The collection includes three film reels relating to Leo Eloesser and sailing and various other films. (7 16mm films)
- Fertig (Lawrence) papers, 1943-1978; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf1r29n4vs (Box 78112: Film Shelf)
  Films relate to U.S. and international economic policy, and laissez-faire economics. (2 16mm films)
- Fighting lady: a drama of the Pacific: motion picture film, 1945; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9r29s1g8 (Box 46007: Film Shelf)
  Film shows the role of aircraft carriers in American naval operations in the Pacific Theater during World War II. (2 35mm, 16mm films)
- Firing Line (Television Program) Broadcast records 1966-1999, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6m3nc88c (Box 80040: Film Shelf)
  Film is about William F. Buckley, Jr. (1 16mm film)
- Frederick (Robert T) papers, 1928-1967; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf200001kx (Box 68009: Film Shelf)
- Free to choose: video tape collection, 1977-1983; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1n39r38j (Box 80201: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film series by Milton Friedman talks about and relates to laissez-faire economics. (10 16mm films)
- Frozen war: America intervenes in Russia, 1973; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt287032vn (Box 80100: Film Shelf)
  The film relates to American intervention during the Russian Revolution. (1 16mm film)
- Gahagan (G. William) papers, 1941-1954; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf4000036t (Box 75057: Film Shelf)
  Collection includes various films about World War II and other subjects. (10 16mm films)
- Garrity (Devin A) papers, 1909-1981; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9s20396n (Box 82032: Film Shelf)
  Collection contains episodes of the television program"Answers to Americans"presented a conservative and anti-communist viewpoint of which Devin A. Garrity was a frequent panelist on the program. (29 16mm films)
- Gibson (Herbert Daskum) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6q2nf2t9 (Box 82024: Film Shelf)
  Film shows army training facilities in Hawaii. (1 16mm film)
- Gray (Ben) papers, 1960; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5r29r707 (Box 80164: Film Shelf)
  Film pertains to American politics and foreign relations in Latin American. (1 16mm film)
- Great Britain. Ministry of Home Security issuances, 1939-1945; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt896nf52c (Box xx434: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films illustrate how to safely dig through bomb debris to rescue survivors, prepared for the civil defense use during World War II. (2 16mm films)
- Grossman (Kurt R) papers, 1913-1973; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf7x0nb2p5 (Box 75026: Film Shelf)
- Hanna (Paul Robert) papers, 1920-1997; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf5s2004dd (Box 77098: Film Shelf)
  Film in the collection pertains to education in the Phillipines. (1 16mm film)
- Hayakawa (Samuel I) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf596nb0jk (Box 82111: Film Shelf)
- Healy (James A) collection, 1896-1966; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf2t1n98v0 (Box xx234: Film Shelf)
  Film in the collection pertains to the Irish uprising of 1916 using archival footage and contemporary footage. (1 16mm film)
- Heisler (Ivan C. F) motion picture film 1938, http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9w103817 (Box 73095: Film Shelf)
  Films show Leon Trotsky, his wife and members of his entourage, and the artist Diego Rivera and his wife, in Coyoacan, Mexico. (1 16mm film)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access. Use copy reference number: 73095_f_0003789.
- Hickey (Robert Ferdinand) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6t1nf0mw (Box 81009: Film Shelf)
  Film is about Admiral Robert Ferdinand Hickey and the USS Hancock. (1 16mm film)
- Hill (Charles) papers, 1955-1972; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf0p3000wh (Box 79067: Film Shelf)
  Films relating to U.S. Ambassador Robert Charles Hill, conditions in and American relations with Latin America and Spain, American foreign policy and domestic politics, and the Republican Party. (9 16mm films)
- Hill (Margaret E) papers, 1942-1948; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9k40380r (Box 79071: Film Shelf)
  Unidentified. (4 16mm films)
- Hiroshima-Nagasaki Publishing Committee motion picture film, 1982; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt4x0nd9wz (Box 82081: Film Shelf)
  Films depict atomic destruction of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, and subsequent condition of survivors of the atomic bomb. (2 16mm films)
- Hoffer (Eric) papers, 1934-1985; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt0n39n6dd (Box 94057: Box 152)
  Collection includes a television interview with Eric Hoffer. (1 16mm film)
- Hoover (Herbert) subject collection, 1916-1964; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf758005bj (Box 62008: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films relate to the career of Herbert Hoover as president of the United States and as relief administrator during World Wars I and II. (133 35mm, 16mm films)
  Use copies of some motion pictures in this collection are available for immediate access.
  "We Fed Our Enemies." Use copy reference number 62008_f_0012444
  "Humanity's Appeal." Use copy reference number 62008_f_0012727
  The following films are available for immediate access: Hetch Hetchy dedication film out-takes https://archive.org/details/csth_00003
  "Herbert Hoover campaign festivities at Stanford University film footage"https://archive.org/details/csth_00004
- Hoover (Herbert): Master of Emergencies motion picture film, 1932; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6k40365f (Box 90093: Film Shelf)
  Film relates to relief work administered by Herbert Hoover, especially that of the American Relief Administration in Russia, 1921-1923. (1 16mm film)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access. Use copy reference number: 90093_f_0008197.
- Hurewitz (J.C) collection, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf8870063c (Box 88012: Film Shelf)
  Unidentified. (1 8mm films)
- Johnson Thomas H. (Thomas Hawkins) papers, 1975; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt8199r2kz (Box 92047: Film Shelf)
  The film shows mathematical pools 24, 25, and 26 in the upper Mississippi and lower Illinois Rivers prepared for the Corps of Engineers by Yung H. Chen and Daryl B. Simons in March, 1975. (1 16mm film)
- Jones (Howard Palfrey) papers, 1930-1973; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf909nb385 (Box 74019: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films include footage of Sukarno. (2 16mm films)
  Humanity's Appeal - Use copy reference number 62008_f_0012727
- Judd (Walter H) papers, 1961-1966; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf4g5003c4 (Box 85003: Film Shelf)
  Films in collection include speeches by Walter Henry Judd and other material relating to foreign affairs and communism. (11 16mm films)
- King (Frank H.H) motion picture film 1946-1947, http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt238nd92p (Box 91021: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film depicts scenes in Shanghai, Peking, Nanking, Yenan and elsewhere in China; members of the American mission to China headed by General George C. Marshall; American food relief distribution in China; communist forces in China; and the Chinese communist leader Zhou Enlai. (1 16mm film)
- Kniazeff (Alex N) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9k40167h (Box 2000C46: Box 26)
  The identified films are home movies. (4 16mm films)
- Kraucs (Eduards) papers, 1945-1977; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1f59r31m (Box 78028: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films relate to Latvian refugees. (3 16mm films)
- Labedz (Leopold) papers, 1960; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt2q2nd9hb (Box 89018: Film Shelf)
  Film shows footage of Boris Pasternak's funeral. (1 16mm film)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access. Use copy reference number: 89018_f_0012672.
- Lademan (Joseph U) papers, 1941-1969; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt82903716 (Box 75002: Film Shelf)
  Film in collection pertains to Captain Joseph U. Lademan and Iwo Jima. (1 16mm film)
- Landau (Saul) papers, 1968-2000; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6q2nf2xv (Box 2001C54: Film Shelf)
  The film pertains to political conditions and revolutionary movements in Latin America. (1 16mm film)